Atik Faysal

Summary

Over three years of experience building applications for Android, update existing android applications and fixing bugs. I like to learn and use new technology in android development. I have worked extensively on various stages of application development with creating & implement application architecture, that includes various stages in development, code signing and releasing to Market and collaborative environments for mobile app on the Android platform.

Experience

Android Developer – 06 Aug 2020 to Present **Monon Soft (JMI Group)**, TMC Building (6th Floor), 52 New Eskaton Road, Dhaka

- Developing software solutions to meet customer needs.
- Creating and implementing the source code of new applications.
- Testing source code and debugging code.
- Evaluating existing applications and performing updated and modifications.
- Developing technical handbooks to represent the design and code of new applications.

Android Developer – 02 Nov 2019 to 20 July 2020 Agami Soft Ltd, Sharif Complex (11th Floor) Puran Paltan, Dhaka

- Created custom mobile applications using native technologies.
- Used specific code versioning tools to manage and implement changes to code.
- Delivered weekly progress report to executive staff and informed applicable parties of upcoming milestones.

Android Developer – 01 Jan 2019 to 30 Oct 2019 STIT BD, 25/2 Lake Circus Road, Dhaka 1205

- Managed all aspects of android app lifecycle from research and planning through deployment.
- Used specific code versioning tools to manage and implement changes to code.
- Tested applications prior to final review to verify efficient issue resolution.
- Update and modify previous app.



Contact

- +88 01647544954
- mdatikfaysal@gmail.com
- s https://tinyurl.com/24cpwcz3
- in https://tinyurl.com/2w2cyday
- 29/1 Toma villa, Shukrabad, Dhanmondi, Dhaka 1209

Skills

- Good knowledge of SDLC
- Good skill of Problem Solving
- Java, Kotlin, PHP, C++, C
- Android SDK, Jetpack
- RxJava, RxAndroid, kotlin coroutines
- MVVM Architecture pattern
- Data Binding, Live Data
- Good Knowledge of Firebase SDK
- Push Notifications,
 Realtime Database, Crash
 analytics, Dynamic Link,
 Authentication
- GPS Location, Map
- MySQL, SQLite, Room
- Version Control System : Git, SVN
- Good responsive design concept

Projects

- JMI ERP: https://tinyurl.com/7yxwcpfr
- Ispahani Agro Ltd: https://tinyurl.com/ybm9lg98
- Salt Cultivation: https://tinyurl.com/y9dvu7w6
- Remedy: https://tinyurl.com/zhb3huev
- Beacon Courier: https://tinyurl.com/87zbrbyv
- Medisheba(Doctor): https://tinyurl.com/3t8h8djw
- Medisheba: https://tinyurl.com/3t8h8djw
- Smart Office Management: https://tinyurl.com/y7azsphn

Online Judge

- UVA Online Judge: https://tinyurl.com/4c3u6b2e
- Codeforces Online Judge: https://tinyurl.com/234mht5a
- URI Online Judge: https://tinyurl.com/wpx5zdm8

More than 500 problem solved in different online judges.

Others

- Champion of DIU Project Fair (DIU 71 Auditorium)
- Trainer of DIU(SWE) Android developer Community

References

Shahid Newaj

Senior Backend Developer at Monon Soft +88 01761913331 msnawajbd@gmail.com

Md Shaokat Hossain

CEO of STIT BD +88 01757769498 Shaokat71@gmail.com

Education

Daffodil International University (2016 - 2020) - Graduation BSC in Software Engineering (3.40)

Qadirabad Cantonment Sapper College (2014) H.S.C Science (5.00)

Baraigram Pilot High Scholl (2012) S.S.C Science (5.00)

Language

- English (Conversational)
- Bangla (Native)